The world, what a glorious place.
Seek freedom, and it will lie
stretched out before your eyes.
If the endless dream guides your restless
spirit, seize it, raise your flag,
and stand tall.
I think back to the time
when my search first began.
I left behind those shores of sand.
For the endless everlasting
world out there.
I know that with this
burning passion I leave me.
Someday, somewhere, I'll finally see the
light I have searched for everywhere?.
When the summer sun is shining.
Shaking the sails of my heart. But I know.
A brand new world
that has been hiding.
Has opened up its doors for me to go.
A great, long blue sky.
Wearing in the tumble waves.
From all despair I can be saved.
For the horizon on the other side is.
And though I travel far
from where my search began.
Over streets of green and shores of sand.
Through the endless
everlasting world out there.
I know that with this
burning passion driving me.
Someday somewhere I'll finally see the
light I will search for everywhere?
Yahoo!
Good God! Thank you!
I can't believe after all the
suffering we've endured to
find Sky Island that it turned
out to be the city of gold!
Which must be your way to reward
me for my good behavior, right God?
You're just great!
Shut up.
Ten minutes ago, you were scared this
god was gonna kill you, remember?
Well, call me shallow,
but I don't care how scared I get as
long as somebody has gold waiting for me.
So do you fear or praise
this god? I'm confused.
All right, I'm done keeping
up with your mood swings.
Ha-ha-ha. Useless.
What is this?
My money says that this is where we're
supposed to find the next ordeal,
which means another priest,
so you two stay awake.
Oh, no.
I think one ordeal is enough
of a nightmare for today.
Which one seems like it could be out here?
String? Iron? Swamp?
I'm so nervous. Relax.
It's just a grassy field.
Open your eyes.
It's not just a field.
It's a field with a thousand impelled
skulls set out like trophies to scare us,
and it's working! You're right.
I wonder who did this.
Hey, what's that smoke?
We're dead!
What's wrong with that guy? Paramecia.
Wiper, we fighting? Not
now. Keep moving. You.
We're ready!
Come on down!
We'll cream you!
Make your move, big guys!
You sound and stink like Blue Sea people,
which means you're the ones
causing all the chaos in Skypiea!
Luffy, that's the gorilla we
saw back on the White Sea. Look!
What got into him?
There's a guy running around out there.
Hey, stop! What do you want?
To destroy you!
Just blow us up and get it over with!
If you don't want to die, then go
back to your blue sea immediately.
Because I promise if you do
anything stupid on this island,
we'll execute you with Enaru.
They're up here trying
to kill this guy, Enaru?
Then that means that these
gorillas are different.
If different means they're not priests,
then that means they don't have to kill us.
So for the sake of keeping all of our body
parts attached, can we please sail on?
Not a chance!
What do you say to a fair fight?
Just you and me!
I'm begging you! Please stop!
You stay on that tree ranch!
I'm coming to you! Usam!
Hands off!
Try to fight here!
Uphold our honor! I have to!
On second thought,
you'll probably end up
killing each other before
you even have a chance to
make it off this island.
I wonder why they're up here.
I'm not sure.
Must be pretty serious.
But they seem to be enemies
of Enteru as well as us.
You know.
I really do hate this place.
Let's keep moving.
I'll cover you!
Get it out of that thing's mouth!
Move in now!
We've been sailing forever, Sanji.
When can we stop?
Can we stop now? Soon.
The sun's going down.
I wonder what we'll run into after dark.
Do you think we can make it
to the altar before then?
No, I don't.
I can barely see the sunset
through those clouds.
I'm surprised they even
have sunsets up here.
We can handle these guys.
Yeah, help the others! Got it.
Chopper!
Where are you, Chopper?
If you can hear me, answer!
Are you there?
Look, her mast is gone and
a wing is ripped in half.
What's he done to her since we left?
Obviously, the Going Merry was attacked.
Chopper couldn't have done that to her.
Chopper!
I'm sorry we took so long!
You can come out now!
You'll be safe! I promise! Yes!
At least give us a sign
that you're not dead!
So I guess that means that he's dead.
Would it kill you to think positive?
Hey, Chipper! Come out!
Because Nomi's scared, and I'm tired!
Hi.
Everything stayed ship-shape
while you were gone.
You don't have to lie to
us, Chopper. Be strong.
Tell us everything that happened.
Please help me as I put a corkscrew.
We're soaking wet.
Check it out.
We found it.
There's the altar with the
Going Mary sitting right on top!
Huh?
Yes!
Mommy! Robin!
I missed you so much!
Sorry to keep you waiting, but I
beat the ordeal of love to get here!
I thought it was fierce, not love.
If that was love, I don't
ever want to find it again!
Anyway, who cares?
We're alive!
Woohoo!
Sounds like they're happy to be here.
Safe and sound.
Where's the… mast?
Uh, look.
I tried, but it didn't
matter how hard I fought.
He still kept burning everything.
I promise I did everything I could. Yeah?
Well, are you going to be okay or what?
You must have been scared
facing that guy by yourself.
It's a good thing he set the mast
on fire instead of you, right?
We can figure out the
details on the ship later.
I promise to become a more
dependable man starting right now!
Chopper, stop yelling at the
altar and tell me something.
How'd you get rid of that priest?
I used the whistle the Sky Knight gave
us, and he showed up to rescue me.
Oh, where is he?
I don't see him.
He's willing to sacrifice
this much for us,
even though he gave us
that whistle for free.
If it wasn't for the sky night,
you guys probably wouldn't have
a ship, and I'd for sure be dead.
I got a bunch of questions for him,
but I guess I'll wait till he wakes up.
We owe you a thanks as well.
Beee!
Luffy!
The Going Mary's trashed,
and it'll be dark soon,
so there's no chance we'll make it
back to Angel Island until tomorrow.
We should hop over to land and
make camp on shore for the night.
Huh? Why there?
Because if we stay here
and someone attacks us,
the first thing to take a
beating will be our ship.
Would you use your head, Luffy?
Not to mention,
it's easier to fight from land than
from an altar floating on a cloud.
This isn't a party,
we're in enemy territory.
Now calm down!
Excellent work!
Now, based on your reports,
we've learned that...
The priests can predict our movements
using a power they like to call Mantara,
and the bird blows flames
and the spear burns you?
But most importantly, we've learned this!
The City of Gold is not a thousand
leagues under the sea as we had thought,
but it is hidden somewhere
on this very island! No way!
That was the first thing I told you!
So, what is this mantra
business all about?
Maybe it's some kind of sixth
sense you only get up here.
Sixth sense?
Yo, Chopper, do I need to
grind this down anymore?
Yes, it needs to be a fine powder.
He suffered a lot of damage
to his digestive system.
This is it an adventure
with gold at the end I can't
wait glad to see someone on
my side I'm ready Luffy no
did you forget what the
scary gorilla guy said about
execution god will be really
mad sounds like fun well we
wouldn't be very good pirates
if we turned our backs
on gold so let's not it won't
be easy you know everybody
up here already hates us
which means I'm in come on
aren't you even a little
frightened of the wrath of God?
I mean, I want to live, don't you?
Gold, and it's all waiting for us!
Kamakiri, you gotta move!
Thanks, I owe you one
after that, Kamakiri.
Kamakiri!
Wiper!
Kamikitty's taking a hit! Huh?
What happened?
Damn.
So close to victory.
But you never even had a chance.
When night falls, we'll have
an even greater advantage.
We're moving out!
Grab all our wounded and meet
back at the rendezvous point!
Now!
You're not getting away!
Om, wait!
What is it?
We have been summoned by God Inaru.
Hmm.
Ah! Boring!
Nobody told you to
watch the boiling water.
You have one job and one job only.
Take the distilled water
and fill up the canteens.
So, make sure that happens.
We'll need fresh drinking water tomorrow.
Hmph. Whatever.
Sanji, we found tons of great stuff!
Excellent.
Let's see the hall.
We found walnuts, aloe, bananas, garlic...
Rats and frogs, too.
Nice, it all goes in the pot.
Disgusting!
You don't expect us to
eat that mess, do you?
Oh, silly me.
Nami, I promise, I'll take the garlic out.
The garlic's the only good thing!
Is our navigator having another meltdown?
Now that's what I call a gem. It's huge!
Big, yes, but it's not a gemstone.
Hey, that's a big salt crystal.
Nice find, Robin, dear.
I found it on the shore.
And I figured we'd find some use for it.
Not only is salt vital to survival, but
without it, my food would taste awful.
If I take half of the garlic and olive,
then I can make antiseptic
and burn ointment?
and use it to heal the Second.
Yeah?
Need any frog?
No, no frog.
Zoro, you're not doing anything.
I got a little job for you.
Oh, Sanji, my swords were not
meant to be used like this.
Yeah, but disobey the chef and you
probably won't eat, so it's your call.
Ah!
You just dropped a rock in the stew!
Is it good?
We don't eat it.
It helps the pot cook.
The stone's heat cooks the
stew from the inside out.
Trust me on this one.
You'll need all the nutrients in
this dish to survive this place.
Perfect, then.
Smells like we got a winner.
Keep your hands off.
Sanji, I'm hungry.
Well, it's not ready yet.
Weren't you just cramming a sky shark
down your gullet not ten minutes ago?
Yeah, but that was just an appetizer.
I figured you knew that.
You must have a rubber stomach, too.
Yeah, tell me about it.
What are you doing, Usopp?
Sanji's almost got dinner laid out for us.
I figured since I wasn't
doing anything anyway,
I'd start hauling this wood
over to the ship for repairs.
You're going to swim over there, huh?
Yeah.
So you don't have a problem
with the giant sharks?
The ship will still be broken tomorrow.
I'll fix it then.
Let's eat, Zoro!
What a moron.
Yes, finished.
Soup's on, but it's ladies first, got it?
Sure.
If you would all please take your seats,
I'll be around with your meals shortly.
And eat up, I don't want it getting cold.
Now, if you would all
listen up while you eat,
I'll explain how we're going
to handle this tomorrow.
Ooh, it looks tasty.
Anyway, let's review Nolan's book first.
He discovered the city of
gold 400 years ago. However,
after leaving the island
and returning with his king,
he found the gold ruins had vanished.
Luckily, we now know what
happened to these ruins.
Keep the ladle handy.
I'll be back for more after I...
Sanji, pay attention!
I was, but he was interrupting you!
The compliment is food and
this is the thanks I get?
Chouchou!
The point I was getting at is that
the gold didn't sink into the ocean,
but was shot up here into the
sky by the knock-up stream just
like we were do you really think a
whole island could have done that
well it's the only thing
that makes sense remember
cricket said that every
time this phenomenon
occurs it's in a different
location yeah that
explosion was enormous i'm
not surprised it lifted
an island it's just
hard to believe that the
forest we're sitting in is
the same one we saw back
on jaya i believe that
has something to do with
the odd composition of
the island clouds up here.
Look at all the trees, fish, and wildlife.
Something about this environment
dramatically increases growth rates,
which explains how a
society here could have
been swallowed up by
these burgeoning forces.
That also explains why the south
birds who saved us were so huge.
I couldn't believe it.
Yeah, 400 years of growing
will do that to a bird.
Then why, here,
why did those south birds
go to such great lengths to
save you Guys um i don't know
but when they saw him they
referred to the sky knight
as god he's god so if We beat
the crud out of this guy
that our job here is done no
genius how'd you get that
out Of what he's saying would
both of you loud mouths just
pipe down yeah shut up yeah
wait who's a Loud mouth you
are you both are can it now
does anyone recall what
nolan's log said about the city
I do!
It's a city of gold!
You're such a dumbass!
Do you ever think before you talk?
I think he wrote about south
birds and a giant gold bell.
Course, there could be a lot more.
The last thing he wrote in the log
before he died was something odd.
It's something I can't figure out,
even after seeing this island.
It says the city of gold
is in a skull's right eye.
That's it. Check it out.
I matched up Robin's
map of Jaya with the old
Skypiea map that we
found in the shipwreck.
Of course, this isn't exact and
there may be some incorrect overlap?
But when you match up
the location of Cricket's
house With the broken
part we found up here,
this is what Jaya looked
like 400 years ago.
Neat! It's a skull!
It is a skull!
Well?
Way to go, Nami!
We did it!
Okay, but where in the skull's right eye?
Hmm, I'm thinking right here.
It's the one structure that's
actually inside the eye.
And no one's found it yet because
of all the people who've tried,
we're the ones who had both maps.
Of course.
We must be lucky pirates.
That kind of makes sense.
Hidden treasure!
Treasure!
The only thing left to do is
make our way to the skull's eye.
But since we can't leave
the ship unguarded,
tomorrow morning we'll split
the crew into two teams.
This is our time.
On the other side of this island waits
more gold than we've ever dreamed.
Now that's what I call gourmet.
Tomorrow we get the gold.
You got it.
You think it'll be sunny again?
We're above the clouds, so I guess yes.
Let's put out the fires
if we don't need them.
It's beginning to get late, you guys.
We don't want to announce
our location to our enemies.
What a rookie move.
You hear that, Usopp?
She wants us to douse the fire.
What are we gonna do?
Huh I don't know it's not really her
fault though she's never been exposed to
this kind of living before we should
be tolerant huh what are you two saying
you're always supposed to have a campfire
when you camp that's what makes it camping
it's never ending with those
idiots hey lay off the sob
stories you know how how
dangerous this island can be,
let's not give it any help in killing us.
Don't care!
We're in the middle of a war.
Between priests protecting their god?
and gorillas forging a coup.
Not to mention the giant
bloodthirsty monsters
that wait around every corner to eat us.
No monsters!
Sky Island scary, Sky Island scary.
Luffy, take a look.
Is this enough wood for your fire?
Can you idiots think for one second?
Don't worry, wild animals
are afraid of fire.
They'll stay away.
But they're surrounding us!
We have to run or we'll die!
Chopper, I think it's trying to talk.
You mind translating?
It's the festival on the
night before gold party! Hey!
This is fantastic!
And you guys really make this stuff?
That's great!
More, please!
Tomorrow the treasure's on!
I'm surprised you're getting along
so well with the Cloud Wolves.
I know of no one else who could have
such raucous festivities on Eneru's land.
It's good to see that you're away.
Are you feeling any better?
I apologize for being
such a burden to you all.
Hey, you're too hard on yourself, old man.
You saved Chopper, and you kept our ship
from being blown to a thousand pieces.
That's my duty.
There's plenty of stew left.
Would you like some?
Thank you.
No, not right now.
Hey!
Thanks for everything,
Second guys! Let's dance!
Dance with the skybox!
Chopper, you been drinking?
Hey, old man, I got a question.
Conis, is she okay?
Very much so.
I've sheltered her and
her father at my house.
They're fine. Great.
I was worried she'd never see me again.
I'm so happy that both of them are safe.
Now, let's celebrate by tossing chopper.
I'm sorry for eavesdropping,
but I heard your earlier
conversation about how
this island was known
long ago by the name Jaya.
Yeah, that's right.
but I believe you have yet to hear the
story of how this island on which we sit
came to be known as such holy ground.
Is this what was so distracting
for you in battle, Lucky?
Are you here to sabotage us?
Get in our way and slow us down?
No, I'm not.
I feel awful for Kamakiri.
We were fighting the priests.
We can't afford to be off-task at all
if we want to make it to God's shrine.
Apologizing won't fix
anything, I know that.
So give that back to me now.
It belongs to Aisa. It's hers.
I promised I would bring
back some birth for her.
Give it back to me, please.
Shut up.
You have to let me have it.
Kamakiri, you shouldn't
even be standing right now.
I can still fight.
You're right about this being our
best time to strike the Upper Yard.
With Satori gone, we proved today that
we can defeat the remaining priests.
I say we attack again
tomorrow at first light.
The ground of the upper yard must remind
you blue sea people of your home far below.
It is similar right it
is yes you're lucky what
you see all around us
and beneath our feet is.
Something that does not
naturally exist in the
sky island cloud can
support plant life but it.
It cannot generate its own.
Greenery and soil are both
foreign things to our life here.
Our people have our own
name for this, its birth.
Those living among the
clouds hold this sacred.
It's what they all desire.
Once we kill Anaru,
There will be no need for you to sneak
around obsessing over a single bag of Fourth.
The time is now.
We will return after 400 years of exile
to the true home of the Shandians.
Aw, come on, Zoro.
Be a pal.
Forget it.
I'm not going with you.
If you're scared, just hold it till
morning and quit whining, you big baby.
I would if I could believe me
just go take a leak by yourself.
That's cold Zoro.
That's really cold
What was that noise?
There shouldn't be anyone
on the ship at this hour.
Geez, this fog is so thick,
I can't see who it is.
Shhh!
Shhh! No!
No!
What's your problem, you moron?
Did you fall asleep mid-piss?
That's pathetic.
I...
saw...
Hey, Usopp, would you snap out of it?
I saw...
a ghost...
a ghost!
Why are we...
Oh
Hey
If you're gonna say something spit it out.
Don't just stand there chewing on your lip
Sorry.
We all know why we're here
because you let wiper get
away instead of killing him
when you had the chance!
Now God Eneru will punish
us all for your failure.
You think you're pretty hot stuff
since you got lucky and beat that fool,
Godfall, don't you, Shit?
Amusing.
Your Majesty, your priests have arrived.
Open the gate.
Not again what are you doing this
is disgraceful you should be ashamed.
Shut up these two have
held me back far too long
just let me unleash my
full power i could take
care of this whole island
myself if it weren't
for these two bunglers
always getting in my way?
Huh, that's some big talk, Shudder.
Maybe it's time for me to teach you
what the true meaning of power is,
if you think you've got the guts.
Let's see if you can
handle the ordeal of iron.
Your ordeal of iron couldn't even
test the strength of a child.
My ordeal of swamp is
the ultimate challenge.
Try that if you're not too afraid.
My Lord Kitetsu, that
looks extremely tiring.
If you want to cross your arms,
you need to hold them like this
and rest them on your chest.
Oh, hey!
Enough!
Cease this chatter!
You're standing in the
presence of God himself!
Really?
I see an empty chair.
I don't see anyone sitting in it.
Surprise, boys!
You asked?
Here I am.
You boys are getting slow.
You're out of practice.
If that pathetic display
is any indication,
you're all well on your way
towards ending up dismal failures
like Satorade.
What is the meaning of this?
Why, God, why do you mock us?
Is that the reason you summoned
us here to entertain yourself?
I was bored.
Now have a seat.
You don't seem to have given too much
thought to the Blue Sea-Dwellers yet,
have you?
God, Inaru, if this is
about Sartori's failure...
That idiot was too inexperienced.
And that ridiculous ordeal of spheres. Ha!
You're hardly in a
position to talk, Shura.
Why they're looking for gold?
That's obvious.
What? Gold?
Impossible How...
how did they know?
This island was originally
part of the Blue Sea.
It's not so odd that they
should know about it.
Of course, they'll move tomorrow!
As will the Shandians.
The rules state that each of you
run an area of the upper yard.
And you're not allowed
to enter each other's
areas or interfere with
one another in any way.
Tomorrow, I'll allow you
to go where you will.
You may set up your
ordeals wherever you want.
There will be no restrictions.
Get as vicious as you like.
Why are you being so
generous all of a sudden?
Because my friends i'm pleased to announce
that the maxim is almost complete.
So it's time for us to put an
end to this wretched island!
and set forth on our journey
to the world of dreams.
It's true!
I wasn't dreaming!
Someone was here last night!
The Going Mary!
She's been repaired!
I knew it!
See, guys, I told you I wasn't insane!
I don't believe it.
The mast is fixed.
Hey, now that's service.
I hate to say it, but
they did a lousy job.
Well, whoever did it sure is nice.
But who'd risk crossing a
river full of sky sharks
to come all the way out here
and fix our ship for us?
I mean, as far as we can tell,
the only people here on Upper
Yard are us and our enemies.
Hey, did you notice they took
all the flying gear off the ship?
That's weird.
I've been thinking about it, and
it's really got me wondering.
Huh.
It just doesn't make any sense to me.
How could this phantom repairman know
what the Mary's supposed to look like?
How did he know she didn't always
have a comb or wings or a tail?
Hmm.
How could he possibly have known?
Come on, Mary.
Just tell me who I saw.
Okay, let's look at the map.
The exploration team will be
taking this route, moving south.
There should be some old ruins
near the Skull's right eye.
Keep an eye out for enemies
and bring back that gold.
Huh, you make it sound so easy.
Hold on, you're the one who keeps
talking about gold and more gold,
but you're not coming?
Well, of course not, it's way too scary.
She wants the gold, but she doesn't
want to risk anything to get it?
That's just too weird!
We'll be in danger too
you know we'll be taking
the mary down river through
the island then we'll
head for the beach near
the ruins we can meet up
here and then we can escape
this stupid sky island?
At long last we'll be a rich and
powerful pirate crew able to buy
anything oh yeah all the meat i
can eat escape that sounds great
look the weather's perfect sure
we're on top of the clouds okay
we'll all meet safely on the east
coast you bet let's get going then!
Who will fall before my ordeal of string?
The Shandians or the Blue Sea-dwellers?
And so the festival begins, magnificent.
Today will be a great day.